Satish Rella

🔀 satish.rella111@gmail.com 📞 8176830395 💡 California USA 🛮 in www.linkedin.com/in/satishr456

https://github.com/satish112?tab=repositories

PROFILE

Experienced Knowledge in software engineering, machine learning, and Data science with a passion to put my analytical, statistical, and programming skillset to collect, analyze, and interpret large data sets to develop datadriven solutions by adding a pinch of seasoning to complicated business challenges on top by utilizing TensorFlow, Keras, Scikit-Learn and ML frameworks.

EDUCATION

Master's, Computer Science, University of Texas at Arlington

01/2019 - 12/2020 | Arlington, United States

M-Tech, Software Engineering, Vellore Institute of Technology

08/2012 - 05/2017 | Vellore, Tamilnadu, India



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Google, Software Engineer (Contract)

10/2021 - present

Mountain view, United States

- Created automated testing cages for efficiently testing the Google Nest products. (Configured Intel NUC for cages)
- Developing scripts and test beds to ensure that the Fuchsia Operating System works on a variety of platforms.
- Refactoring and optimizing code for software applications, debugging tools, and testing frameworks.
- Designing Python scripts to automate test runs for various test bed configurations.

TEKaroon Solutions, Software Engineer

03/2021 - 09/2021

Elkridge, Maryland, United States

- Developed a J2EE/Java application using Spring Boot, works on multi-layer architecture to reduce complexity
- between the service layer which has business logic for the project and the repository layer interacting with a
- database.
- Consumed RESTful web services in the application. Used POSTMAN to check all REST API endpoints are
- working fine. JSON data is generated from these API calls.
- Implemented Spring Data JPA dependency which utilizes Crud Repository, having all built in logic for CRUD
- operations. Imported all the dependencies for the project using Maven. Used Query methods which helps in
- reducing code for queries

Tata Consultancy Services, Software Engineer (Project: AIG)

06/2017 - 12/2018 | Hyderabad, India

- We match the Treaty policies with the customer requirements and resolved the Service now tickets.
- Rescheduled and rewrite the Jobs in COBOL for effective health check of all applications and reporting the results.
- Used .XML Log files for checking Error exception handling.
- Enhanced the user interface of business application for the ease of use and resolved the support tickets.

Uptec Idealabs Private Limited, IoT Intern (Project: Ambience

12/2015 - 01/2016 | Hyderabad, India

Checkup Using Wireless Sensor Network)

- Designed and implemented a wireless sensor network that monitored the weather conditions.
- Collected the data from the node to Raspberry Pi using wireless systems.
- Pushed the collected data to an IoT analytics platform to visualize the data with every one-minute interval for updates of weather conditions from each node

PROJECTS

Portfolio-Website

- Developed a personal website using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript and bootstrap is used for styling.
- Hosted the application on Amazon web services (AWS)
- Migrated the whole project through MVC Framework (Laravel), later it deployed in the cloud.

Image Caption Generator Using CNN-LSTM

- Extracted the features of every photo from the convolution layers of VGG16 and RESNET50 models.
- Converted the text input to vector using the word embedding layer followed by LSTM.
- Predicted the caption of photo by merging the feature and word embedding vectors, processed by a dense layer

Face Detection from YouTube Data using Open CV:

- Collected the data with a specific date, time, location, length of video using API and extracted the faces in Keyframes of video.
- Using pre-trained machine learning classifier "ResNet50" and "Siamese Network" to find the face in public videos of YouTube.

Data modelling with PostgreSQL and Apache Cassandra

• Created database schema and built ETL pipeline (Python) to analyze the data of the Music streaming app.

Client-Server System (SNMP)

- Designed a client-server program in DOCKER using Socket Programming in python using CLI Library.
- Communicated between client and server, broadcast the messages, and share files between each other.
- Implemented a distributed locking system between the multiple servers on shared files.

Implemented 2PL

- Implemented a two-phase locking (2PL) protocol for concurrency control.
- The protocol to be implemented will be rigorous 2PL, with the wound-wait method for dealing with deadlock

Analyzing Sports data with NOSQL

• In this project, we used Mango DB as an example of a document-oriented NOSQL system, and see how data is stored and queried in such a system

Data Mining (Mini Projects)

- Statistical Exploratory Data analysis, Aggregation & filter & Ranking, Visualization conducted guided exploration on Federal Emergencies and Disasters dataset to identify the different patterns in data for further analysis.
- Decision tree, Naive Bayes classification, and K-Nearest Neighbor implemented on the Cardio dataset to find the active patients.
- K-means clustering, Hierarchical Agglomerative clustering models applied on Adult Dataset to locate who earned more than \$50,000 or not, and to visualize clusters for predicted and actual cluster labels.
- Apriori algorithm with different support & confidence was applied to the Shopping cart Dataset to find which items were sold.

Forecasting NIKE Revenue Data:

- Forecasted the Revenue of Nike Revenue data using Linear Regression, K-Nearest Neighbors, Pyramid-Arima, and FBProphet.
- K Fold ross Validation on the each of the model using training data for comparison of performance of models (with 5 Folds).

CERTIFICATES

• Udemy -Python for Data Science

- LinkedIn- Advanced SQL for Data Scientists
- LinkedIn Tableau Essential Training (2020.1)